It is preferable not to travel with a dead man.
Dead Man is a drama, fantasy, western film directed by Jim Jarmusch.
On the run after committing murder, an accountant encounters a strange Native
American man who prepares him for his journey into the spiritual world.
William Blake, played by Johnny Depp.
Nobody, played by Gary Farmer.
Train Fireman, played by Crispin Glover.
Cole Wilson, played by Lance Henriksen.
Conway Twill, played by Michael Wincott.
Johnny 'The Kid' Pickett, played by Eugene Byrd.
Dead Man is a 1995 American acid Western film
written and directed by Jim Jarmusch.
It stars Johnny Depp, Gary Farmer, Billy Bob Thornton, Iggy Pop, Crispin Glover, John Hurt, Michael Wincott,
Lance Henriksen, Gabriel Byrne, Mili Avital, and Robert Mitchum in his final film performance.
The movie, set in the late 19th century, follows William Blake, a
meek accountant on the run after killing a man.
He has a chance encounter with enigmatic Native American spirit-guide "Nobody", who
believes Blake is the reincarnation of the visionary English poet William Blake.
Described by Jarmusch as a "Psychedelic western", the
film is shot entirely in monochrome.
Neil Young composed the guitar-dominated soundtrack with portions
he improvised while watching the movie footage.
The film explores themes of dying and death,
sheriff, bounty hunter, gun, indigenous.
The tone is emotional.